American Philosophical Society Archives 1743-1984 APS.Archives
American Philosophical Society
- Communications, 1748-1837; III; 4.0 ln. ft.
  - Manuscript communications, 1748-1837; III.1; 3.5 ln. ft.
    - Letter to Benjamin Franklin [received], 1787 Sept. 21; 1.0 item (Box 4)
    - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin?], 1790 May; 1.0 item (Box 4)
    - Letter to Robert Patterson, 1800 Oct. 1; 1.0 item (Box 4)
    - Letter to David Rittenhouse [received], 1791 May 20; 1.0 item (Box 4)
      Note: c.f. minutes p. 194. For enclosure see article on "warming rooms" 1791, March 7.
    - Concerning how to cause a mill to go by bellows and how to raise water above the level, 1789 Nov. 20; 1.0 item; Lewis, Alexander (Box 4)
    - Account of an instrument ALS to discover the distance ALS to an object, 1789 Nov. 20; 1.0 item; Lewis, Alexander (Box 4)
    - Concerning the prevention of decay in peach trees, 1797 Dec. 15; 1.0 item; Lime (pseud) (Box 4)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1799 June 26; 2.0 items; Livingston, Robert F. (Box 4)
      Note: includes an illustration of "Livingston's Steam Engine".
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1802 July 16; 1.0 item; Logan, George, 1753-1821 (Box 4)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1821 Aug. 4; 1.0 item; Long, Stephen Harriman, 1784-1864 (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1824 April 2; 1.0 item; Long, Stephen Harriman, 1784-1864 (Box 4)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1817 Mar. 7; 1.0 item; Long, Stephen Harriman, 1784-1864 (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Maskell Patterson, 1825 Feb. 3; 1.0 item; Long, Stephen Harriman, 1784-1864 (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Maskell Patterson, 1825 Mar. 18; 1.0 item; Long, Stephen Harriman, 1784-1864 (Box 4)
    - ALS to G. G. Bogart, 1817 May 28; 1.0 item; MacNaly, Leo (Box 4)
    - ALS to William Smith, 1776 Sept. 25; 1.0 item; Madison, James, 1751-1836 (Box 4)
    - ALS to David Rittenhouse, 1780 Nov.; 1.0 item; Madison, James, 1751-1836 (Box 4)
    - Thermometrical observations at William and Mary College, 1780.Nov.; 1.0 item; Madison, James, 1751-1836 (Box 4)
    - Concerning education, 1797 June 16; 1.0 item; Magaw, Samuel (Box 4)
      A.D.S. 11p. Entered for the premium.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1816 Sept. 2; 1.0 item; Mansfield, Jared (Box 4)
    - ALS to Moses Bartram, 1771 Mar. 23; 1.0 item; Marshall, Humphry (Box 4)
    - ALS to William Smith, 1769 Dec. 11; 1.0 item; Maskelyne, Nevil (Box 4)
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin, 1769 Dec. 11; 1.0 item; Maskelyne, Nevil (Box 4)
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin, 1769 Dec. 27; 2.0 items; Maskelyne, Nevil (Box 4)
      Note: includes photocopy of original text.
    - Concerning the growth of plants, 1780 June 16; 1.0 item; Matlack, Timothy, 1736-1829 (Box 4)
    - Concerning fireplaces, 1811 Feb. 1; 1.0 item; Matlack, Timothy, 1736-1829 (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Maskell Patterson, 1828 Jan. 27; 1.0 item; Matthews, Thomas J. (Box 4)
    - ALS to Thomas Francis Gordon, 1835 Nov. 2; 1.0 item; Maxwell, Thomas (Box 4)
    - ALS to Caspar Wistar, 1798 July 30; 1.0 item; May, Fancis (Box 4)
    - Concerning a saw mill, 1803 Mar. 24; 1.0 item; McCalla, Andrew (Box 4)
    - ALS to American Philosophical Society, 1838 Oct. 31 1831 Nov. 11; 2.0 items; Mease, James (Box 4)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1821 Sept. 06; 1.0 item; Meigs, Josiah (Box 4)
    - Memoir on experiments on meat, 1804 Aug. 12; 1.0 item (Box 4)
    - Memoir on making seawater drinkable, 1803; 1.0 item (Box 4)
    - Meteorological observations, 1748 Aug.-1749 Sept.; 1.0 item (Box 4)
    - Meteorological observations, 1764 Dec. 31-1765 Jan. 26; 1766 July 11; 1.0 item (Box 4)
    - Meteorological observations, 1763 Jan. 30-1766 Dec. 30; 2.0 items (Box 4)
    - Meteorological observations, 1775; 1.0 item (Box OS)
    - Meteorological observations, 1817 Dec. 1- 1819 April 30; 1.0 item (Box OS)
    - Meteorological observations: Taken at Lake Erie, 1798 July 4- Sept.30; 1.0 item (Box OS)
    - Meteorological observations: Taken on a ship from Philadelphia to Calcutta, 1798 March 23- June 30; 1.0 item (Box 4)
    - Method of extinguishing fire in a chimney, n.d.; 1.0 item (Box 4)
    - Subscription list for proposed exploration of the American West., 1793; 1 document, 41 x 33 cm.; Michaux, André, 1746-1802 (Box OS)
      Discovered in the vault in Philosophical Hall in 1979; accessioned, 1980; see Committee on Library Report, Year Book (1979): 158-160.
      This stunning document, the body of which is in the hand of Thomas Jefferson, gives instructions to Michaux "to explore the interior country of North America from the Mississippi along the Missouri and Westwardly to the Pacific Ocean.. ." Those subscribing money for this venture have signed below, with their pledges noted. Included are: John Adams, Alexander Hamilton, Thomas Jefferson, James Madison, Robert Morris. This expedition was never undertaken, and it is only one instance of Jefferson's continuing interest in exploring the western territory, culminating in the Lewis and Clark expedition of 1804-1806.
    - Concerning an offer of a marble copy of the zodiac of Denderah, Egypt, 1.0 item; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855 (Box 5)
    - A concise method of extracting the cube root, 1835 Nov.; 1.0 item; Miller, George W. (Box 5)
    - ALS to Caspar Wistar, 1800 July 5; 1.0 item; Mitchill, Samuel L., (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831 (Box 5)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1800 May 14; 1.0 item; Mitchill, Samuel L., (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831 (Box 5)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1805 Dec. 12; 1.0 item; Mitchill, Samuel L., (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831 (Box 5)
    - Concerning icebergs, 1805 Dec. 20; Mitchill, Samuel L., (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831 (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1806 Nov. 5; 1.0 item; Mitchill, Samuel L., (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831 (Box 5)
    - ALS to the Archbishop of Ireland, 1815; 2.0 items; Molyneux, Thomas (Box 5)
      Note: includes illustrations of elephant teeth found in Northern Ireland.
    - ALS to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 Feb. 10; 3.0 items; Montgomery, Alexander (Box 5)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1813 Feb. 5; Moriniere, Simon-Barthelemy-Joseph Noel de la (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1820 Jan. 31; 2.0 items; Mower, T.G. (Box 5)
      ote: includes a "Diary of the Weather at Cantonment Missouri for January 1820".
    - ALS to Thomas T. Hewson, 1804 Sept. 22; 1.0 item; Mugford, William (Box 5)
      Magellanic Premium prize winner. For report of committee, see: APS. Report..., 1805 Feb. 13 (APS Archives).
    - Narrative: Respecting an Hindoo woman who lately burnt herself on the Funeral pile of her husband (Box 5)
      See Washington, George to John Adams, 1798 Sept.25.
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1771 Feb.; 2.0 items; Naso (pseud) (Box 5)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1819 Jan. 12; 1.0 item; Nelson, Hugh (Box 5)
    - ALS to Rev. St. George, Bishop of Clagher, 1715 July 29; 1.0 item; Nevil, Francis (Box 5)
    - Concerning meteorites, n.d.; 1.0 item; Nichols, Francis (Box 5)
    - A new and simple method of producing decisions in certain cases by the way of chance, 1805 June 21; 2.0 items (Box OS)
      Note: Enclosed is copy communicated by Patterson
    - ALS to ..., 1781 Feb. 20; 1.0 item; Nicola, Lewis, 1717-1807 (Box 5)
    - Plans for a rain gage, 1781 Feb. 19; 1.0 item; Nicola, Lewis, 1717-1807 (Box 5)
    - Delineation of a solar shadow, 1771 Dec. 12; 1.0 item; Oliver, Andrew (Box 5)
      Note: illustration
    - ALS to William Smith, 1774 April 25; 1.0 item; Oliver, Andrew (Box 5)
    - On fireplaces, 1796 Oct.16; 1.0 item (Box 5)
    - Concerning the air pump, 1824 Jan. 21; 2.0 items; P.C. (Box 5)
      Note: includes diagram
    - ALS to James Madison (1), 1777 July 7; 1.0 item; Page, John, 1744-1808 (Box 5)
    - ALS to James Madison (12, 1777 July 7; 1.0 item; Page, John, 1744-1808 (Box 5)
    - [to Henry Muhlenberg], 1811 Nov. 17; 1.0 item; Palisot de Beauvois, M. (Box 5)
    - Papers relative to the fonts of type of Fournier Le Jeune, 1809 April 21; 3.0 items (Box 5)
    - Il y a dans, n.d.; 1.0 item; Parangon (Box OS)
    - ALS to Jonathan Williams, 1811 Oct. 30; 1.0 item; Partridge, Alden (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1808 Feb. 10; 1.0 item; Patham, William (Box 5)
    - ALS to Stephen Duthil, 1807 Nov. 28; 1.0 item; Patrullo, Gerard (Box 5)
    - Translation of ALS to Stephen Duthil, 1807 Nov. 28; 1.0 item; Patrullo, Gerard (Box 5)
    - Verbal communications, 1801 Feb.-Mar.; 1.0 item; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854 (Box 5)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1802 Nov. 1; 1.0 item; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854 (Box 5)
    - Concerning Chapman's steam boat, 1810 July 27; 1.0 item; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854 (Box 5)
    - Specific gravity of a meteoric stone, 1808 April 8; 1.0 item; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854 (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1813 Dec. 3; 1.0 item; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854 (Box 5)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1810 April; 1.0 item; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854 (Box 5)
    - ALS to William Hembel, 1804 July 16; 2.0 items; Patton, Tristram (Box 5)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, [1802] Feb. 5; 1.0 item; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860 (Box 5)
      Natural History. Friday, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Refers to skeleton given by T.Jefferson FILM199 FRAME348
    - Proposed method of finding the quadrature of the circle, 1826 Feb. 1; 1.0 item; Peck, Jacob (Box 5)
    - Concerning the origin of coal, 1834 May 16; 1.0 item; Pedder, James (Box 5)
    - Meteorological observations from Newton township and Philadelphia, 1773 June 9- Sept. 30; 1.0 item; Pemberton, Israel (Box 5)
    - Meteorological observations near Philadelphia, 1775 Jan. 1-Feb. 28; 1.0 item; Pemberton, Israel (Box OS)
    - Concerning cholera, n.d.; 1.0 item; Percente, Francesco (Box 5)
    - Method of roofing a house with tin in Canada, 1826; 1.0 item; Percival, William (Box 5)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, Robert Hare, and Eugenius Nulty, 1819 June; 1.0 item; Perkins, Jacob (Box 5)
    - Journal and experiments on his bathometer and pyrometer (1), 1819 Nov. 5; 1.0 item; Perkins, Jacob (Box 5)
    - Journal and experiments on his bathometer and pyrometer (2), 1819 Nov. 5; 1.0 item; Perkins, Jacob (Box 5)
      Note: includes diagrams.
    - ALS to William Jones, 1808 July 12; 1.0 item; Perrier, George (Box 5)
    - ALS to Jonathan Williams, 1798 March 26; 1.0 item; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828 (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1804 Sept. 22; 1.0 item; Pinckney, Charles Cotesworth (Box 5)
    - Plan of a surveying quadrant, n.d.; 2.0 items (Box 5)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1824 Nov. 25; 1.0 item; Plantou, Anthony (Box 5)
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin, 1788 Oct. 1; 1.0 item; Pleasants, James B. (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1837 July 28; 1.0 item; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851 (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1837 Aug. 21; 1.0 item; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851 (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1827 April 20; 1.0 item; Poinsett, Joel Robertson (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1827 Sept. 6; 1.0 item; Poinsett, Joel Robertson (Box 5)
    - ALS to the President of the American Philosophical Society, 1835 April 25; 1.0 item; Porter, James (Box 5)
    - Composition of enamel of kitchen utensils, 1801 Oct. 5; 1.0 item; Priestly, Joseph (Box 5)
    - Question concerning the probable effects of Napoleon's return from Elba, ca. 1815; 1.0 item (Box 5)
    - ALS to David Rittenhouse, 1788 April 10; 4.0 items; Retrograde (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1805 June 6; 1.0 item; Richarson, Joseph (Box 5)
    - ALS to Benjamin Rush, 1811 Mar. 15; 3.0 items; Ridgely, Frederick (Box 5)
      Note: Includes illustration of a saltpeter cave.
      - An Eye-Draught of the Mammoth-Cave in Warren County, Kentucky, 1811 Mar. 15; 1.0 map, 40.6 x 25.4 cm; Ridgely, Frederick
        The covering letter addressed to Benjamin Rush states that "the needle does not traverse" the cave, therefore the "Eye-Draught."
        Realms of Gold, 2 (5).
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1793 Jan. 18; 1.0 item; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796 (Box 5)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1793 Feb. 15; 1.0 item; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796 (Box 5)
    - Account of a gold mine in Georgia, 1832 Sept. 15; 1.0 item; Robertson, George (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1815 Jan. 7; 1.0 item; Robinson, J.D. (Box 5)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1801 April 08; 1.0 item; Robotham, Richard (Box 5)
    - Concerning a loom, 1811 Aug. 3; 1.0 item; Rodgers, Richard C. (Box OS)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1838 Aug. 28; 1.0 item; Rumker, Charles (Box OS)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1788 May 2; 1.0 item; Rumsey, James, 1743?-1792 (Box 5)
    - Description of a machine for cleansing chimneys, 1786; 1.0 item; Rumsey, James, 1743?-1792 (Box 5)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1791 Feb. 17; 1.0 item; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813 (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1791 Nov. 25; 1.0 item; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813 (Box 5)
    - The subscriber offers the Rapid Jack to the public [donated by T. Green], 1810 Dec. 7; 1.0 item; Sacket, Augustus (Box OS)
    - An explanation of the Rapid Jack [donated by T. Green], 1810 Dec. 7; 2.0 items; Sacket, Augustus (Box OS)
    - Advertisement, 1828 Oct. 14; 1.0 item; Sanseer Machine Co. (Box 5)
      See Mease, James, to Sanseer Machine Co.; 1831 Nov. 11
    - Meteorological observations at Natchez, 1802 Feb. 1-June 1; 1.0 item; Sargent, Winthrop, 1753-1820 (Box 5)
    - Details of the rise and fall of the Mississippi River at Natchez, 1799 Jan. 1-1818 Dec. 31; 1.0 item; Sargent, Winthrop, 1753-1820 (Box OS)
    - From the meteorological observations at Gloster Place, two miles south of Natchez., 1810-1819; 1.0 item; Sargent, Winthrop, 1753-1820 (Box 5)
    - Plan for a compositor's, printer's and bookseller's rule showing how many 1000 ems or squares are in any page of type, 1810 April 06; 1.0 item; Saunders, Samuel Hyde (Box 5)
    - Concerning light (1), 1830 May 21; 1.0 item; Saunders, Samuel Hyde (Box 5)
    - Concerning light (2), 1830 May 21; 1.0 item; Saunders, Samuel Hyde (Box 5)
    - Concerning light (3), 1830 May 21; 1.0 item; Saunders, Samuel Hyde (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1832 Oct. 18; 1.0 item; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834 (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1832 Sept. 5; 1.0 item; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834 (Box 5)
    - ALS to Isaac Hays, 1832 Dec. 1; 1.0 item; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834 (Box 5)
    - List of his mechanical inventions, 1789; 1.0 item; Schultz, William (Box 5)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. President, 1791 Oct. 25; 1.0 item; Scrupulous (Box 5)
    - Concerning the effects of heat and cold on springs, 1791 Nov. 4; 1.0 item; Scrupulous (Box 5)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. President, 1792 Nov. 23; 1.0 item; Scrupulous (Box 5)
    - Anallysis of maclurite, 1822 May 17; 1.0 item; Seybert, Henry (Box 5)
    - ALS to a friend of the Abbe de Mably, 1784 Dec. 30; 1.0 item; Sharp, Granville (Box 5)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1797 Nov. 7; 1.0 item; Shultz, Benjamin (Box 5)
    - ALS to Caspar Wistar, 1807 June; 1.0 item; Shultz, Benjamin (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1815 May 24; 1.0 item; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864 (Box 5)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1802 Dec. 17; 1.0 item; Simplicity (pseud) (Box 5)
    - Sketch of an item to be manufactured, n.d.; 1.0 item (Box OS)
    - ALS to Henry Drinker, 1805 Dec. 17; 1.0 item; Smith, Richard (Box 5)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1798 Mar. 30; 1.0 item; Smith, Samuel Harrison (Box 5)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1800 Dec. 20; 1.0 item; Smith, Thomas P. (Box 5)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. President, 1826 Aug. 12; 1.0 item; Southard, Samuel Lewis (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1801 Aug. 18; 1.0 item; Spalding, Lyman (Box 6)
      Medicine, Anatomy, and Physiology. Portsmouth, A.L.S. 3p.and add., end. Concerning vaccinations
    - ALS to John Redman Coxe, 1803 Feb. 21; 1.0 item; Spalding, Lyman (Box 6)
    - Concerning the origin of meteorites (1), 1810 Feb. 02; 1.0 item; Spalding, Lyman (Box 6)
    - Concerning the origin of meteorites (2), 1810 Feb. 02; 1.0 item; Spalding, Lyman (Box 6)
    - Concerning the origin of meteorites (3), 1810 Feb. 02; 1.0 item; Spalding, Lyman (Box 6)
    - Steam Engine, 1798; 1.0 item (Box 6)
      Note: diagram. p> Mechanics, Machinery, Engineering, etc.
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson (1), 1818 April 12; 1.0 item; Steel, Hugh (Box 6)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson (2), 1818 April !2; 1.0 item; Steel, Hugh (Box 6)
    - ALS to Thomas Bond, 1782 Nov. 4; 1.0 item; Stonemetz, George (Box 6)
    - ALS to Thomas Bond, 1782 Nov. 4; 1.0 item; Stonemetz, Jacob (Box 6)
    - To Issac Lea, 1839 Oct. 21; 1.0 item; Storer, David Humphreys (Box 6)
    - ALS to David Rittenhouse, 1796 Feb. 29; 1.0 item; Story, Isaac (Box 6)
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin, 1789 May 22; 1.0 item; Stroebel, John Christopher (Box 6)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1829 May 30; 1.0 item; Swift, Joseph G. (Box 6)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. President, 1818 June 17; 1.0 item; Symmes, John Cleves (Box 6)
    - ALS to Timothy Matlack, 1781 Sept. 29; 1.0 item; Syng, Philip (Box 6)
    - Synoptic table of the characteristic properties of alkalis and Earthly salts, 1.0 item (Box OS)
    - Remarks on the fattening and curing of beef as could be best practiced in America, 1786; 1.0 item; T. (Box OS)
    - Table of transit of Mercury, 1799 May 7; 1.0 item (Box OS)
    - Memoir sur les relations Commerciales des Etats-Unis avec l'Angleterre, 1809; 1.0 item; Talleyrand-Perigord, Charles Maurice (Box OS)
    - A Concise Abstract of ... Tertiary Fossil Shells ...., n.d.; 1.0 item; Taylor, Richard C., (Richard Cowling), 1789-1851 (Box 6)
    - ALS to the President of the American Philosophical Society, 1826 Jan. 20; 1.0 item; Taylor, Sicard and Company (Box 6)
    - ALS to Ferdinand R. Hassler, 1812 Oct. 3; 1.0 item; Taylor, Thomas (Box 6)
    - Thermometrical Measurements at Detroit, 1797 July 1-31; 1.0 item (Box OS)
    - Thermometrical Observations, 1803 May 1- 31; 1.0 item (Box 6)
    - Thermometrical Observations taken at Calcutta, 1798 Aug 10- Nov. 30; 1.0 item (Box 6)
    - Concerning some newly discovered islands and shoals in the Indian Ocean, 1802 Sept. 2; 1.0 item; Thomas (Box 6)
    - Concerning the Aurora borealis, 1773 April 2; 1.0 item; Thomson, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. Secretary, 1835 May 6; 1.0 item; Thornton, B. (Box 6)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1805 Dec. 13; 1.0 item; Thornton, William (Box 6)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1806 Jan. 1; 1.0 item; Thornton, William (Box 6)
    - Concerning the AJE, 1825 Oct. 29; 1.0 item; Tiran, Prisciliano (Box OS)
    - An enquiry in ALS to the ways of proving cast iron cannons (English translation), 1802 Jan. 4; 1.0 item; Tousard, Louis (Box 6)
    - An enquiry in ALS to the ways of proving cast iron cannons (French original), 1802 Jan. 4; 1.0 item; Tousard, Louis (Box 6)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1798 June 11; 1.0 item; Turner, G. (Box 6)
    - ALS to William Jones, 1820 Jan. 27; 1.0 item; U.S. Commissioners of the Navy (Box 6)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1837 Feb. 13; 1.0 item; U.S. Department of State (Box 6)
    - ALS to Robert Walsh, 1819 April 7; 1.0 item; United States. Department of War (Box 6)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. President, 1792 Dec. 13; 1.0 item; Valltravers, Johannes Rodolph (Box 6)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1795 May 29; 1.0 item; Valltravers, Johannes Rodolph (Box 6)
    - Concerning water, dioptics, burns and scalds, salt of lime, heat and cold, and the dead in the grave, 1797 Mar. 17; 5.0 items; Vanleer, Branson (Box 6)
    - Plan for extinguishing fires, 1795 Mar. 6; 1.0 item; Varle, Charles (Box 6)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1798 Feb. 1; 1.0 item; Varle, Charles (Box 6)
    - ALS to Caspar Wistar, 1806 Nov. 20; 5.0 items; Varle, Charles (Box 6)
      Note: includes transcription; illustration of plans for the construction of a lock for the canal of Susquehanna in Maryland.
    - Concerning canals and navigation of rivers, 1807 Feb. 6; 3.0 items; Varle, Charles (Box OS)
    - ALS to American Philosophical Society. Vice President, 1814 Jan. 22; 1.0 item; Varle, Charles (Box 6)
    - Concerning a cheap method to build locks for inland navigation, 1807 Feb. 6; 1.0 item; Varle, Charles (Box 6)
      Note: originally filed with "concerning canals and navigation of rivers", Feb. 6 1807.
    - Concerning outdoor privies in cities, 1814 Jan. 22; 1.0 item; Varle, Charles (Box 6)
    - Concerning the cause of yellow fever, 1814 Feb.; 1.0 item; Varle, Charles (Box OS)
    - Concerning the making of lime, 1807 Feb. 6; 4.0 items; Varle, Charles (Box OS)
    - Commentary on Baron's paper on the power of numbers (1), 1805 July 19; 1.0 item; Vaughan, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - Commentary on Baron's paper on the power of numbers (2), 1805 July 19; 1.0 item; Vaughan, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - Commentary on Baron's paper on the power of numbers (3), 1805 July 19; 1.0 item; Vaughan, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - Commentary on Baron's paper on the power of numbers (4), 1805 July 19; 1.0 item; Vaughan, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - Commentary on Baron's paper on the power of numbers (5), 1805 July 19; 1.0 item; Vaughan, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - Commentary on Baron's paper on the power of numbers (6), 1805 July 19; 1.0 item; Vaughan, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - Commentary on Baron's paper on the power of numbers (7), 1805 July 19; 1.0 item; Vaughan, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1825 Oct. 14; 1.0 item; Vaughan, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - ALS to Benjamin Rush, 1784; 1.0 item; Vaughan, Benjamin (Box 6)
    - Concerning the great coldness of Maine and Massachusetts, 1809 April 3; 1.0 item; [Vaughan, Benjamin?] (Box 6)
    - ALS to Andrew Ellicott, ca. 1803; Vaughan, John (Box 6)
      See Ellicott, Andrew, to Robert Patterson, 1803 Oct 1.
    - ALS to Albert Gallatin, 1807 April 28; 1.0 item; Vaughan, John (Box 6)
      Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1 p. Copy. Enc. wanting. Forward's Ferrer's ideas on a survey of the coast of the U.S. For copy of enclosure, see letter from Ferrer to J. Vaughan; April 25, 1807.
    - ALS to Robert Walsh, 1834 Dec. 15; 1.0 item; Vaughan, John (Box 6)
    - ALS to Heinrich Christian Schumaker, 1838 Aug. 14; 1.0 item; Vaughan, John (Box 6)
    - ALS to Petty Vaughan, 1835 Aug. 14; 1.0 item; Vaughan, John (Box 6)
    - Memorandum concerning communication about Norse relics in North America, 1828 Dec; Vaughan, John (Box 6)
      See Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, to John Vaughan, 1828 Dec. 17.
    - Memorandum on the destruction of pine trees by a worm, 1804 Oct. 5; Vaughan, John (Box 6)
      See Pinckney, Charles Cotesworth, to John Vaughan, 1804 Sept. 22.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1825 May 18; 1.0 item; Vaughan, William (Box 6)
    - Analysis of the Nicotiana latifolia, 1809 Jan. 12; 1.0 item; Vauquelin, A. (Box 6)
    - Analysis of snuff, 1809 Sept. 15; 1.0 item; Vauquelin, A. (Box 6)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1792 June 13; 1.0 item; Vaux, James (Box 6)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1792 June 25; 1.0 item; Vaux, James (Box 6)
    - Concerning steam paddles for boats and mills, 1809 July 21; 2.0 items; Voigt, Henry (Box 6)
      Note: includes diagram of paddles.
    - Observations on the Phalaeenatinea, etc., 1812 Nov. 1; 1.0 item; W., J. (Box OS)
    - ALS to unidentified correspondent, 1835 July 3; 1.0 item; W.R. (Box 6)
    - Meteorological Observations made at Washington (1), 1823 April 18- 1824 April 18; 1.0 item; Wallenstein, Jules de (Box 6)
    - Meteorological Observations made at Washington (2), 1823 April 18- 1824 April 18; 1.0 item; Wallenstein, Jules de (Box 6)